《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
我的药物有用
My cure will work.
或者把他们变成了超能力者
Or turn them into meta-humans.
开始对患者1-A
Beginning biopsy examination
进行活检测试  米切·罗梅罗
on Patient 1-A, Mitch Romero.
所以我想成为一位为超能力者辩护的律师
I want to become a defense attorney for meta-humans.
宝贝  你知道你能帮助这座城市里
Babe, do you know how many people
多少人吗
you could help in this city?
我听说你们招实习的
Hi, I'm here about the internship.
欢迎加入《公民报》
Welcome to "The Citizen."
为了让几十亿人在这次危机中存活
In order for billions to survive,
闪电侠必须死
the Flash must die.
我要亲自去看看这个危机
I'm gonna go see this Crisis for myself.
唯一你们都活下来的时间线  就是我死了
The only timeline where you all survived was if I died.
那我们怎么和他们说
So what do we tell them?
闪电侠失踪  消失于危机之中
不管我们怎样做
Whatever we're gonna do,
2019年
都不能告诉团队我将会死
we can't tell the team I'm gonna die.
伙计们  把这些加入我们的货单
Add all these to the inventory, boys.
明天的买卖能大赚一笔了
Tomorrow's bake sale is gonna be a real treat.
谁死了轮到你说了算了
Who died and made you boss?
米切·罗梅罗
Mitch Romero.
还是没有他的消息吗
Still no word from him?
那只能表示罗梅罗失踪了  又不是死了
That makes Romero missing, not dead.
干我们这一行的  有区别吗
In our line of work, what's the difference?
你们现在都是我的手下了
This is my crew now.
分头去看看  不管是谁  干掉他
Fan out. Whoever's here, put him down.
罗梅罗
Romero?
闪 电 侠
第六季
第三集
监视者
The Monitor?
你在哪见到他的
Where did you see him?
把切斯特关进精神增强室之后
We went in the Time Vault,
我们进入了时间穹顶见到了他
right after putting Chester in the MAC.
他去年提到的危机
The Crisis that he spoke about last year,
跟基座中报纸上显示的是同一个事件
it's the same one in the plinth's newspaper.
而事件并不是在2024年发生
And it's not coming in 2024.
而是在十月十号发生
It's coming December 10th...
就在2019年
2019.
-你确定吗  -那个混蛋在骗你
- Are you sure about this? - The jackass lied to you.
我们开始也是这么认为的
Yeah, well, we thought so, too, but...
巴里去了地球三
Barry went to Earth-3,
杰伊·加里克帮助他确认了那是真的
and Jay Garrick helped him see that it was true.
他怎么做到的
How did he do that?
杰伊将我未来的意识投射了出来
Jay projected my mind forward into the future.
你看到了什么
Okay. And what did you see?
我看到巨量的反物质
I saw a giant wave of anti-matter
横扫了我们的地球
sweeping over our Earth.
将中城和所有人都化为了灰烬
Vaporized all of Central City and everybody in it.
也包括你们三人
Including you three.
很好  我去日程表上标记我的死期
Great. I'll go mark my calendar.
我们仍有三周时间来阻止这一切的发生
We still have seven weeks to make sure none of this happens.
大伙  巴里说的没错
Guys, Barry's right.
我们以前也曾改变过未来
We've changed the future before.
我们可以再次改变它
We can change it again.
那个阿斯加德人扮相的监视者还说什么了
So what else did our Asgardian cosplayer say?
就说了这么多
That was pretty much it.
乔来信息了
It's Joe.
中城警局找我  不过那边可以缓一缓
Needs me at CCPD, but that can wait.
我们得着手处理这件事
We--we need to get on this.
我们应该把所有时间投入这件事情
Yeah, we should spend every minute we have on this.
不  大伙  我们应该
No, guys, look, what we should do
暂缓一下好好想清楚
is take a well-deserved time-out
明天再继续讨论
and come back tomorrow with clear heads.
好的  听你的
Okay. If you think so.
现在怎么办
What now?
我得让他们对即将到来的事情做好准备
I have to prepare them for what's coming.
他们需要在没有我的情况下也能继续前行
They have to be ready to go on without me.
我想我知道该先从谁开始
I guess I know who I need to start with.
妈妈
Mom?
拉尔夫
Ralphy!
拉尔夫  过来  宝贝儿子
Ralph, oh, come here, baby.
-愚蠢的手铐  -发生什么了
- Those stupid things. - What happened?
昨晚十点
Last night, 10:00 p.M.,
M大街的当铺被持械抢劫了
the Avenue M pawn shop was robbed at gunpoint.
当铺老板指认你妈妈为凶手
The shop owner ID'd your mom as the perp,
我们不得不拘留她
so we had to hold her.
罪名还未决定
Charges pending.
德比太太  这位是塞西尔·霍尔顿
Mrs. Dibny, this is Cecile Horton.
回见  拉尔夫
Ralph.
祝你好运
Good luck.
塞西尔  我妈妈过去确实犯了不少事
Look, Cecile, yes, my mom has an eventful past, but...
抢劫  盗窃  贿赂...
Okay, robbery, larceny, bribery...
十四项指控
14 allegations.
没有一项被定罪了  裙摆完美的小姐
Not a single charge, Miss Perfect Hemline.
谢谢
Thank you. Um...
口供上说当铺老板亲自
Ooh, it says here that the owner of the pawn shop
指认你为抢劫犯
personally identified you as the robber.
好吧  我去过店里  但不是在十点
Okay, I was in the shop, but not at 10:00.
我五点左右就走了
I left around 5:00.
那么抢劫是在五小时后发生的
Okay, so the robbery was, like, five hours later,
妈妈  你十点左右在哪里
so, Mom, where were you around 10:00?
这真的有这么重要吗
Is it really that important?
等等  昨天是这个月的第二个星期一
Wait, yesterday was the second Monday of the month,
所以  妈妈
so, Mom...
我在橡树街那家荣耀干洗店
I was at the Cleaner's Royale on Oak.
好的  干洗店
Okay, dry cleaners.
其实是个赌场的门面
It's a little bit of a gambling front.
妈妈  我最后一次去那里还是
Wow, Mom, the last time that I was there was when...
你和马弗·佩雷斯在一起的时候
when you and Marv Perez were an item.
愿他安息
May he rest in peace.
小拉夫  我真的不认为
Well, Ralphy, I really don't think
在赌场的人会帮我找到不在场证明
anyone there is gonna help with my alibi.
只有去试试才知道
There's only one way to find out.
实地取证
Road trip.
乔认为此案可能涉及到了超能力杀手
Joe thinks there's a meta-killer that might be involved,
所以如果有人问起的话
so if anybody asks,
你就说自己是我的超能力顾问
you're my meta-human consultant.
附近大楼里的保安听到了枪声
The security guard from a nearby building heard the gunshots.
说这里听起来像战区
Said it sounded like a war zone.
我们还没找到足够的残肢
We haven't found enough body parts
来证明是哪个黑帮团伙干的
to determine which crew did all this.
他浑身都是爪印
He's covered in claw marks.
是动物干的  可以走了吧
An animal did this. Good to go?
不  这不是动物的血
No, we're not. This--this isn't animal blood.
还有两具尸体  或者说残肢
There's two more bodies, or what's left of them,
还有很多那种东西
and a lot more of whatever that is.
我看到了一条...两条手臂
I see one arm, two arms.
它们属于同一个人
Hm. They're from the same person.
我会分析一下的
I'll analyze this.
希望这能帮我们找到凶手
Hopefully, it'll lead us to our killer.
多谢
Thank you.
你能分析一下她是怎么了吗
Can you analyze what's going on with her?
我在努力分析了
Yeah, I'm trying.
冰霜  冰霜  你在做什么
Frost! Frost, what are you doing?
这些枪里没有子弹
There's no ammo in these.
我认识这些枪
I know these guns.
它们是靠暗物质作为弹药的
They're charged with dark matter.
现在它们都是空的了
They're all empty.
谁会为了暗物质杀人
Who would kill for dark matter?
一个懦夫
A coward.
抓到你了
Gotcha.
你做了什么
What did you do?
冰霜  你在做什么
Frost, what are you doing?
你应该听我指挥  而不是
You're supposed to be following my lead, not--
让凶手招供
Getting a damn murderer to confess?
没有证据证明他涉及此案
There's no evidence he's involved.
松开
Ease up.
放开他
Let him go.
凯特
Cait?
你是冰霜杀手
You're Killer Frost?
事实上  她就是我  可怜鬼
Actually, she's me, Sad Coffee Guy.
非常抱歉  我叫巴里·艾伦
I am so sorry. My name is Barry Allen.
我是中城警局的一名鉴证专员
I'm a forensic scientist with CCPD.
我们正在调查一系列涉及超能力者的谋杀
We're investigating a series of meta-related murders,
凯特琳和冰霜是我的超能力顾问
and Caitlin and Frost are my meta-human consultants.
我是拉姆齐·罗素医生
Dr. Ramsey Rosso.
你的实验室发生了什么
What happened to your lab?
我加班的时候有人闯进来了
Um, somebody broke in while I was working late.
犯罪现场也有这种物质
This same substance was at our crime scene.
我认为袭击你的超能力者
I think the meta that attacked you
就是我们要找的那个人
is the person we're looking for.
我们在找的那个人
The guy we're looking for
从一个走私仓库偷走了暗物质
stole dark matter from a stash house.
我这里确实有少量暗物质
I did have a small amount of dark matter here.
-你从哪得到它的  -从以前的同事那
- Where'd you get it from? - From an old colleague.
泰德·科德
Ted Kord.
他实实在在愿意帮助我的研究
He was actually willing to help me with my research.
外面有人在寻找暗物质
Well, someone's out there hunting for dark matter,
他为了得到它  不惜杀人
and he's willing to kill to get it.
所以不管你在研究什么
So whatever it is you're working on--
艾伦先生  我的噬血细胞综合征研究很重要
Look, Mr. Allen, my HLH research is very important.
我的母亲死于这种疾病
I lost my mother to this disease.
既然你说在这里找到了
Now, you mentioned you found a similar substance,
和犯罪现场一样的物质
both here and at your crime scene.
而且说实话  我从未见过这样的物质
And, honestly, it's unlike anything I've seen before.
我是一名血液病专家
Well, I am a blood specialist.
也许我能帮上点忙
Perhaps I could be of some assistance.
你不会真的要相信这个人吧
You are not actually gonna trust this guy, are you?
-我可不信  -抱歉
- 'Cause I don't. - I'm sorry.
冰霜
Frost...
有人危在旦夕了  好吗
People are dying out there, all right?
如果罗素医生能给我们提供任何帮助
If Dr. Rosso can help us in any way,
那么我愿意接受  你也应该如此
then, yeah, I'm open to it, and you should be, too.
你会帮助我们吗  罗素医生
Would you help us, Dr. Rosso?
叫我拉姆齐就好
Please, call me Ramsey.
早上好  老大
Morning, boss.
我手里一个大的猛料
I have got the mother of all scoops,
托福于你的新实习生
and thanks to your new intern,
这将是中城公民媒体的独家报道
it's gonna be a CCC Media exclusive.
实际上  我是想着
Actually, you know, I was hoping
你能帮我弄一下新的文件分类系统
that you would help me with the new filing system.
字母排序就好
Alphabetical is great.
昨晚麦克洛奇技术公司被闯入了
So there was a break-in at McCulloch Tech last night.
没有东西被偷
Nothing was stolen,
但你绝对想不到犯人是谁
but you'll never guess who the perp is.
看  哈里森·威尔斯还活着
Get this. Harrison Wells is alive.
你从哪里弄到这个的
Where'd you get this?
麦克洛奇的一个安保人员和我有老交情
One of the McCulloch security guards and I go way back.
干得好
Nice work.
这样吧
Um, I'll tell you what.
我来调查一下这事  与此同时
I will look into this, and in the meantime,
那个市长的报道需要引用些他人的看法
I could use some quotes on that mayor story.
市政厅想要知道
The city council's wondering how long
这一届能持续多久
this new one's gonna last.
我更想要调查这个
Uh...I'd rather do this.
阿莱格拉  我明白的  好吗
Allegra, look, I understand, okay?
我以前也是个有野心的新人记者
I was an ambitious cub reporter once, too.
这件事你办的很棒
You know, this is great work,
但是从现在开始我接手了  好吗
but I will take it from here, okay?
好吧
Fine.
拉尔夫小子
Ralphy boy!
好久不见了
Long time no see.
-看起来挺精神  -谢了  托尼
- Looking trim. - Thanks, Tony.
-黛比  -你好  托尼克
- Deb. - Howdy, Tone-Loc.
我需要帮个忙  托尼
I need a favor, Tony
是是  M大街的当铺
Yeah, hi, the Avenue M pawn shop
昨晚被打劫了
was robbed last night,
警察认为是黛比干的
and the police think that Debbie was responsible.
我们需要你安保摄像头的录像
We just need the footage from your security camera
这样我们就可以证明妈妈昨晚在这里
so we can prove that Mom was here last night.
昨晚  对  黛比在这里
Last night? Yeah, Deb was here.
太好了
Great.
但是我不和警察合作
But I don't work with the cops.
家规如此
House policy.
再说  你知道我这里没摄像头的  黛比
Besides, you know I don't have cameras in here, Deb.
-那盆栽  -酒吧那个丑台灯
- Potted plant. - Ugly lamp on the bar.
烟雾警报器  一  二  三
Smoke detectors one, two, three.
我喜欢你  拉尔夫  你猜怎的
I like you, Ralphy. Guess what?
-可以把录像给你  -太好了
- You can have the footage. - Oh, great.
-要5000美元  -抱歉  什么
- For 5,000 bucks. - I'm sorry, what?
等你有了票子之后再来找我
Come back and see me when you got the green.
很高兴见到你  拉尔夫小子
Good to see you, Ralphy boy.
这条道不通了
That was a bust.
好吧
Oh, well.
等等  等下  妈妈
Wait, wait, wait, hang on, hang on, hang on, Mom.
我们或许没有钱  但是我们可以赚来
We might not got the green. We can earn it.
-对  -抱歉  往下边看
- Right. - Uh, excuse me, down here.
我们要怎么赚来
How exactly are we going to earn it?
看我的  亲爱的
Watch me, sweetie.
那么  我能和凯特说话吗
So can I talk to Cait?
她现在能听到我吗
Can she hear me right now?
首先  是冰霜  我重新给自己定位了
One, it's Frost. I'm rebranding.
然后  当然  她想的话就能听到你
And two, sure. She can if she wants to.
凯特琳  我想解释一下
Caitlin, I want to explain myself.
关于从科德工业买下暗物质一事
About purchasing dark matter from Kord Industries.
我希望你能理解  如果有哪怕一点机会
I hope you understand if there's any chance
可以拯救更多的生命
of saving more lives...
你就会把握
You're gonna take it. Right.
我本不想背着你干这种事
I didn't want to go behind your back,
但你拒绝帮助我
but you refused to help me.
已经不在听了
Not listening anymore.
而且你从没告诉我你是个超能力者
And you never told me that you were a meta.
我还以为我们挺亲近的  凯特
I thought we were closer than that, Cait.
看来你俩的交情没有你认为的那么深
Huh. Guess you two aren't as good of friends as you thought.
各位  中城警局找到了我们那超能力者
Hey, guys, CCPD got back a DNA match on our meta.
米切·罗梅罗
Mitch Romero.
-你知道这名字吗  -不
- Do you recognize the name? - No.
米切·罗梅罗是中城
Mitch Romero is the head
最大枪械交易组织的头目
of Central City's biggest gun-running operation.
怎么了  我下面也有朋友的
What? I have friends in low places.
罗梅罗昨晚一定是在寻找暗物质
Romero must've been looking for dark matter last night
他去了他知道绝对能找到的地方
when he went to the only place he knew he'd find it.
他的库存
His own stash.
为什么要打劫自己还杀了所有员工
Why rob yourself and then kill all your employees?
有人刚闯入了水星实验室
Someone just broke into Mercury Labs.
那样的设施里会有
A facility like that would have
不知多少的暗物质
undisclosed amounts of dark matter.
你做了什么
What did you do?
你做了什么  冰霜
What did you do? Frost!
你杀了他
You just killed him!
我们应该把超能力者拷起来
We're supposed to cuff metas,
而不是把他们扔出窗外
not throw them out windows.
冷静点
Calm down.
罗梅罗没事  你看他都站起来跑掉了
Romero is fine. He just got up and walked away.
你把他甩出窗外的时候
You had no idea that would happen
可没有考虑过他的死活
when you shot him out the window.
你被自己的愤怒支配了
You let your anger get the better of you.
我以为你能控制好
I thought you had a handle on that.
冰霜  下不为例
Frost! That cannot happen again.
怎么  你还有资格让我控制情绪
What, now you're telling me how to feel?
我只有七个星期的时间指导你
Look, I have seven weeks to teach you
如何处理这样的情况
how to handle this kind of situation.
你必须好好听我指挥
You have to start listening.
那你得做一个更好的老师
You have to stop being such a crappy teacher.
一定不能让她赢
Make sure she loses.
托尼的安保录像
Tony's security footage
在他办公室的U盘里
is on a USB drive in his office.
尽可能帮我拖住他
Buy me as much time as you can.
好  没问题  交给我们  你快去
Okay, it's fine. We got it. Go.
好了
Okay.
他很紧张
He's nervous.
上  押注
Go. Do it.
对十
Pair of tens.
班门弄斧
Can't bluff a bluffer.
顺子
Boom.
开什么玩笑
You're kidding me.
黛比今晚手气旺
Debbie's hot tonight.
黛比  我的天  黛比
Uh, Debbie. Oh, Deb.
全押上
All in.
等着哭吧
Read 'em and weep.
这把输的很惨  黛比
Ooh, tough break, Deb.
抱歉老妈  我们尽力了
I'm sorry, Mom. We tried.
咱们回家吧  很高兴见到你  托尼
Let's get you home. Good to see you, Tony.
继续努力你的违法事业
Keep up the not-so-legal work.
杀手凯特琳去哪了
Where's Killer Caitlin?
又在外面毫无根据地骚扰其他嫌犯吗
Out assaulting another suspect without cause?
她在休息
She's taking a breather.
样本里有没有发现些什么
Did you find anything helpful from the sample?
简直超乎我的想象
More than I ever imagined.
你看这些基因的转录模式
Take a look at the pattern of these gene transcriptions.
罗梅罗受暗物质感染的细胞
Romero's dark matter-infused cells
正在摧毁他正常的细胞
are destroying his normal cells.
他现在更接近于怪物
He's more monster now than man.
吸收的暗物质越多
The more dark matter he absorbs,
他就会变得越强壮
the stronger he gets.
照这么看
According to this,
罗梅罗24小时前就已经死了
Romero's been dead for over 24 hours.
所以才杀不死他
That's why he can't die.
他已经死了
He already has.
感谢你的帮助  罗素医生
Um, thank you for your help, Dr. Rosso.
-巴里  -怎么了
- Barry. - Yeah?
如果能让我观察
If I could observe Romero's genes
罗梅罗的基因与暗物质结合的过程
interacting with dark matter,
我也许能找到逆转的方法
I might be able to find a way to counteract his condition.
这恐怕不太好
I don't think that's a good idea.
研究暗物质非常危险
Working with dark matter can be really dangerous.
艾伦先生  我可是整个西半球
Mr. Allen, I'm the top hematologic oncologist
最顶尖的血液肿瘤学家
in the western hemisphere.
外面这个生物
There's a creature out there
携带着具有扩散性的血液化学成分
with a metastasized blood chemistry
拥有着比拟十个人的力量
with the strength of ten men,
他每分钟都在变强
and he's getting stronger by the minute.
请你让我协助你们
Please, let me help.
卫星面部识别系统不到一小时前
The satellite's facial recognition spotted
发现了咱们的新威尔斯
our new Wells less than an hour ago.
根据米兰达的消息  就在这附近
According to Miranda, it's somewhere in this area.
哈里森·威尔斯  欢迎来到一号地球
Harrison Wells, welcome to Earth-1.
我叫西斯科·拉蒙
My name is Cisco Ramon.
你为什么要跟踪我
Why are you following me?
真棒  又是个易怒的
Oh, great. Another angry one.
你的目标是这块无价之宝吗
To get your hands on this priceless beauty?
是这样吗  动手啊
Is that why? Go ahead.
它能让所有的受害者
It gives nightmare hallucinations
陷入噩梦的幻觉
to all of its victims.
要不要试试
Would you like that?
-要不要试试  -不要
- Would you like that? - No!
看来
So...
-是你  -什么
- It's you. - What?
-你叫什么名字  -爱瑞丝·韦斯特·艾伦
- What's your name? - Iris West-Allen.
爱瑞丝
Well, Iris--
再惹老娘试试
And don't you forget it.
我自己能解决
I had that.
就是这里
And there you are.
等一下  不对  不  不
Wait. Oh, no, no, no.
黛比
Debbie, um...
录像显示你九点半就离开了
that has you leaving at 9:30.
我们需要知道你十点钟的时候在哪里
We need to know where you were at 10:00,
在抢劫发生的准确时间
the exact time of the robbery.
我当时出去透气了  没办法  咱们尽力了
Went out for air. Oh, well. We tried.
等下  室外还有另一个相机角度
Hang on, there's another camera angle outside.
小拉夫  别...
Ralphy, don't...
找到她了吗
Did you find her?
是的
I did.
和马弗·佩雷斯一起
With Marv Perez.
马弗还活着
Marv's alive?
是的
Yeah.
你说他几个月前死于一场车祸
You said he died in a car accident months ago.
当铺被抢时...
You were with...
你和马弗一起
Marv when the pawn shop was robbed.
小拉夫  听我解释
Ralphy, let me explain.
如果马弗活着  你的其他男朋友呢
If Marv is alive, what about your other boyfriends?
他们当中还有多少活着
How many of them are alive?
好吧  所有
Okay. All of them.
拉夫  你知道吗  没事的
Ralph, hey, you know what? It's okay.
这是个好事情
This is-- this is a good thing
因为马弗是黛比的不在场证明
because Marv is Debbie's alibi,
所以你妈不会进监狱了
so your mom isn't gonna go to jail.
是的  让我们关注在这点上
Yeah, let's focus on that.
马弗  道格  克雷格  尼克  这些人  他们
Marv, Doug, Craig, Nick? These guys, they...
他们对我来说像家人一样
They were like family to me.
你怎么能对我撒谎呢
How could you lie about that?
我不知道你为什么不开心  亲爱的
I don't know why you're so upset, sweetie.
你总是很快就能忘掉他们
You always moved on so quickly.
我这么坚强是为了你
I was being strong for you.
但不意味着每次都不会伤心
That doesn't mean it didn't hurt like hell every damn time.
-到底发生什么了  -就是很常见的
- What really happened? - What always happens.
你知道  我们很开心
You know, we were happy,
但我知道不会长久  所以我就切断了
but I knew it wouldn't last, so I ended it.
你还撒了哪些谎
What else did you lie about?
-爸爸真的离开我们了吗  -是的
- Did Dad really leave us? - Yes.
那个是真的
That one is true.
小拉夫  我不是故意要伤害你的
Ralphy, I didn't mean to hurt you.
我叫拉夫
My name is Ralph.
你走吧
You need to leave.
出去
Get out.
立刻
Now.
我不敢相信你和凯特能在这工作
I can't believe you and Cait get to work here.
这些东西怎么会帮上忙
How will all this help?
暗物质是神奇的东西
Dark matter is a miraculous thing.
通过基因拼接  我能用你的暗物质样本
With gene splicing, I can use your dark matter samples
给罗梅罗的血液充负电荷
to negatively charge Romero's blood.
这样应该能弱化他  让你执行逮捕
That should weaken him enough for you to make an arrest.
但是...
But, um...
我...
I, uh...
我还需要一台离心机
I will need a second centrifuge.
楼下还有一个
Oh. Uh, there's another one downstairs.
我去拿
I'll get it.
我对你有种感觉
I had a feeling about you.
我希望我是错的
I hoped I was wrong.
但我一眼就能认出绝望的人
But I know a desperate man when I see one.
把它们放回去
Put them back.
-不  -我可以逼你
- No. - I can make you.
那就继续吧
Go on, then.
正如你所说  我是一个绝望的人
Like you said, I'm a desperate man.
我没什么可以失去的了
I have nothing to lose.
我以为你想拯救生命
I thought you wanted to save lives.
HLH不仅是我妈得的病
HLH isn't just my mother's disease.
它先杀死了她  现在正在杀死我
First it killed her, and now it's killing me.
我还是不能让你拿走那些
I still can't let you take those.
看看它那对米切·罗梅罗造成了什么
Look at what it did to Mitch Romero.
我每天在日历上做标记  直到死亡
I am marking a calendar every day until I die,
等着跌落悬崖
waiting to fall off a cliff,
没有能力抓住任何东西或任何人
powerless to grab onto anything or anyone.
我看着我妈从同样的悬崖上跳下去
I watched my mother dive off that same cliff...
脸上还带着微笑
with a smile on her face.
她甚至没有反抗
She didn't even fight.
我知道失去母亲是什么感觉
I know what it's like to lose your mother.
我知道你很生气
I know you're angry.
这不是愤怒
This isn't anger.
这是我愤怒之下的痛苦
This is the pain beneath my anger.
与死亡斗争需要勇气
It takes courage to fight death.
或许接受死亡需要的更多
Maybe it takes more to accept it.
我妈脸上也有过这种表情
My mum had that same look on her face
就在她被确诊的那一天
when she was first diagnosed.
你也是将死之人  对吗  巴里
You're a dead man, too. Aren't you, Barry?
你为什么不为自己做斗争呢
So why don't you fight for yourself?
我在日历上标记我所剩日子
I'm marking my calendar with the days I have left to live.
我会在余下的日子尽可能多拯救生命
And I'm gonna spend them saving as many people as I can.
你不是懦弱
You're not a coward.
你只是太天真
You're just naive.
米切·罗梅罗还逍遥法外
Mitch Romero's still out there.
你说你想要拯救生命
You said you wanted to save lives.
证明一下  帮我阻止他
Prove it. Help me stop him.
或者离开我的实验室
Or get out of my lab.
我们开始吧
Let's get to work.
我不理解你  巴里
You know, I don't understand you, Barry.
你无畏地走向死亡
You march towards death without fear,
就像妈妈一样
just like Mum.
这种力量你是从哪里得到的
Where is it you get your strength?
大概是跟她获得的地方一样
Probably the same place she did.
从我爱的人身上
People I love.
原来如此
I see.
一定很难开口告诉他们吧
Well, it must've been incredibly hard to tell them.
你也是将死之人
You're a dead man, too.
对吗  巴里
Aren't you, Barry?
一定很难开口告诉他们吧
Well, it must've been incredibly hard to tell them.
这不是愤怒
This isn't anger.
这是我愤怒之下的痛苦
This is the pain beneath my anger.
根据他这个滑稽的小腰包上写的
According to his techno fanny pack,
这个归哈里森·纳什·威尔斯博士所有
this belongs to Dr. Harrison Nash Wells.
冷静
Easy.
-我们不会伤害你的  -不会的
- We're not gonna hurt you. - No.
我们重新开始
Let's just try this again.
我是爱瑞丝·韦斯特艾伦
All right, I'm Iris West-Allen.
-他是西斯科·拉蒙  -爱瑞丝和西斯科
This is Cisco Ramon. - Iris. Cisco.
我们是威尔斯委员会的朋友
And we are friends of the Council of Wells.
那些蠢货啊  好吧
Those idiots. Okay, now.
听着  我电击过你一次
Okay, listen, I tased you once before,
也不介意再来一次  所以...
and I'm happy to do it again, so just...
我让你电的  别乱动
I let you do that. Now hold still.
你来我们地球做什么
What are you doing on our Earth?
我来做什么  我来找一件合成品
What am I doing? I'm searching for an artifact
它所含有的粒子恰好...
that just happens to contain the same particles...
与你身上散发的相同
I'm currently reading off you.
-什么  -然而...
- What? - Although...
什么粒子  什么的粒子
What--what part-- particles of what?
恒金
Eternium.
Eternium?
恒金是一种多元宇宙元素
Eternium is a Multiversal element, all right?
不过小巷里的读数要高一些
Although the readings were stronger in the alley.
听着  印第安纳
Listen, Indiana,
我不知道你那个世界怎么办事
I don't know how they do things on your Earth,
《印第安纳·琼斯》电影系列之一
但这不是《魔宫传奇》
but this ain't "Temple of Doom."
然后恒金到底是个什么
And what is Eternium supposed to be, anyway?
提基  波利尼西亚神话中人类的始祖
某种从提基之神偷来的神秘元素
Some kind of stolen mystical element from the tiki gods
突然之间需要你来送还吗
that you suddenly have to return?
这世上没有什么神秘的胡扯或者神灵
Look, there's no such thing as mystical mumbo jumbo or gods.
有的是超能力者  外星人
What there are are meta-humans, aliens,
和被头脑单一的人崇拜的假神
and false gods worshiped by simple-minded people
那些人只能在神话中寻求安慰
that find comfort in myths.
我打破那些神话
I dispel those myths.
而你们你一点用也没有
You people are no help.
最新报道  纳什
Newsflash, Nash.
这类对话我们之前进行过
We've actually done this dance before.
-是吗  -是的
- Is that right? - That's right.
通常开始得并不顺利  尤其是你我之间
It usually starts off rocky, especially between you and me,
但最终  我们还是走到了一起
but eventually, we bond,
而你学会了拥抱自己感性的一面
and you learn to embrace that sensitive side.
所以为什么你干脆就别装模作样了
So why don't you just drop the act,
向我展示出我所了解的
and show me that warm,
你热情  有同情心  聪明的一面
compassionate, smart guy that I know you to be.
让我问你一个问题
Let me ask you a question.
我看起来像是想紧握你双手的样子吗
Do I look like I want to hold hands?
这下有意思了
Interesting.
要想拿回你的东西  大概不得不握住了
If you want your toys back, you might just have to.
不得不承认  这招挺酷的
I have to admit. That was pretty cool.
她知道多元宇宙的事吗
Does she know about the Multiverse?
她现在恐怕是知道点了
She kind of does now.
我来处理吧
I'll handle it.
我收集了市长故事需要的引述
I got the quotes for the mayor story,
还完成了你的归档工作
and I finished your filing.
-都按照首字母顺序排列整齐了  -很好
- Everything's alphabetical. - Great.
还有就是  我不干了
Also, I quit.
阿莱格拉  等下
Allegra, wait.
你知道为什么我为什么要出来吗
You know why I was even out here?
享受阳光
Enjoying the sun.
在铁山监狱是晒不到什么太阳的
You don't get much of that in Iron Heights.
我在那里被关了五年
I spent five years locked up there,
我学会了如何分辨
and it taught me how to tell the difference
告密者和撒谎精
between a snitch and a liar.
你不是告密者
You're not a snitch.
阿莱格拉  不是你想的那样  好吗
Allegra, it's not what you think, okay?
算了
Forget it.
我在监狱里已经浪费够多时间了
I've wasted enough time behind bars.
不会再浪费时间替一个撒谎精工作了
I'm not wasting any more working for a liar.
所以跟我说实话  不然我立马就走
So be honest with me, or I'm out of here.
好吧  你说的没错
Okay. You're right.
我对你撒谎了  但我没法告诉你
I was lying to you, but I can't tell you the truth
关于哈里森·威尔斯的真相  现在不行
about Harrison Wells, not yet.
我是相信你的  阿莱格拉
I do believe in you, Allegra.
我认为你的直觉很准
I think you have great instincts,
我也认为你会成为一名优秀的记者
and I think you're gonna make a great reporter.
这也是为什么我给了你一个机会
That's why I took a chance on you.
现在我要请你给我个机会  行吗
Now I'm asking you to take a chance on me, okay?
相信我
Trust me.
等时机合适的时候  我会全盘托出
When the time is right, I will tell you everything.
我保证
I promise.
我们是记者
We're journalists.
我们的工作就是告诉人们真相
It's our job to tell people the truth,
而不是控制真相
not control it,
即便真相难以启齿
even if it's tough to say,
或难以让人接受
or hard as hell to hear.
这是心里话  老板
Just saying, boss.
明早见
See you in the morning.
你是来对我继续对我说教的吗
Come to lecture me some more?
听着  我知道你觉得自己愤怒的时候
Look, I know you think that you fight better
打架更厉害
when you're angry,
所以  何不试试打一个真正的目标
so why don't you try and hit a real target?
别虚张声势  要真的打到我
Stop trying to hit me, and hit me.
你为什么就不愿承认事实
Or why don't you just admit the truth
是什么伤害了你
about what's hurting you?
我不想刚开始生活就死去
I don't want to die when I've just started living.
好吗
Okay?
我终于有机会过正常的生活
I finally have the chance to live a life,
现在这个愚蠢的危机却要夺走一切
and now this stupid Crisis is gonna take it all away?
我知道这不公平
I know it's not fair.
你知道芭斯罗缤冰淇淋有31种不同的口味吗
Do you know that Baskin-Robbins has 31 different flavors?
我可能还没搞清楚最喜欢哪种口味
I might die before I get to figure out
就已经死了
which one is my favorite.
死前连自己最喜欢哪首歌都不知道
Or what my favorite song is,
也来不及开一次生日派对
or have my first birthday party.
我在这世上存在了30年却从没开过生日派对
30 years of existing, and I have never had one.
这真的很糟心
That really sucks.
冰霜
Frost.
危机总会有
There's always gonna be a crisis,
也许会有某个超能力者威胁要
or some meta-human that's threatening
杀死你爱的人
to take away the life that you love.
事实是  我们都生活在借来的时间里
Truth is, we're all living on borrowed time.
那又怎样  大家都总是感觉这么糟糕吗
So, what, everybody feels this crappy all the time?
这确实能让我感觉好点
That actually does kind of make me feel better.
所以你不能因为可能会失去明天
It's why you can't let the threat of losing tomorrow
就放弃活在当下
keep you from making the most of today.
我想用今天剩余的时间来
I want to spend the rest of today
确保米切·罗梅罗不再伤害任何人
making sure that Mitch Romero doesn't hurt anyone else.
你到底是什么
What are you?
住手
Stop!
放开我
Let me go.
罗梅罗
Romero!
拉姆齐  别动
Ramsey, don't move.
你要这个吗
You want this?
是吗
Yeah?
好  过来拿吧  过来
Yeah, come and get it. Come on.
来  过来拿
Come on. Come and get it.
快来
Come on!
冰霜  罗梅罗往管道监狱去了
Frost, Romero's heading to the pipeline.
在这呢  快来
Hey, there. Come on.
对了
Yeah.
来吧
Come on.
好玩的都结束了
Oh, I miss all the fun.
下次需要监禁不死超能力者的时候
Next time we have to lock up an undead meta,
都交给你来办
he's all yours.
巴里
Uh, Barry.
看来那些超能力者手铐是白费功夫了
Guess those meta-cuffs would've been a waste of time.
暗物质会助长他的怒火
Dark matter fuels his rage.
好  退后
All right, get back.
我要向他发射闪电了
I'm gonna throw a lightning bolt at him.
不不不  我有个更好的主意
No, no, no, I have a better idea.
给我尖端科研实验室里所有的暗物质  马上
Get me all the dark matter in Star Labs. Now.
那会让他变得更强大
That's gonna make him stronger.
不  会让他变得更愤怒
No, it's gonna make him angry,
而且我很肯定  如果我们把暗物质都给他
and I'm pretty sure if we give it to him,
他就会摄入过量
he'll overdose.
相信我
Trust me.
让怒火燃烧吧  罗梅罗
Rage on this, Romero.
你是对的
You were right.
愤怒确实会影响判断
Anger really does cloud judgment.
没有骨折  只有瘀伤
No breaks, just bruising.
你运气不错
You got lucky.
我必须得走了
I must be off.
拉姆齐
Ramsey, hey, um...
我知道今天我们有些分歧
I know we didn't see eye to eye today,
但还是感谢你帮忙
but thanks for your help.
如果你想谈谈...
If you ever want to talk...
谢了  我没事
Thanks, but I'm fine.
来生再见  巴里
See you in the next life, Barry.
拉尔夫·德比
私家侦探社
谢谢你过来  妈妈
Thanks for coming, Mom.
你在开玩笑吗
You kidding?
我只是很感激你愿意见我
I'm just so grateful you would see me.
能先听我说吗
Can I go first?
你父亲走后
When your father left,
你整整一周每天早上都来我房间
you came into my room every morning for a week
手叉着腰问"爸爸去哪了"
with your hands on your hips, and you said, "Where's Dad?"
我也不知道怎么告诉你他不会回来了
And I did not know how to tell you he wasn't coming back.
我很担心
I was so worried
你会认为那是我的错或者怪到你身上
that you would think it was my fault, or worse, yours.
之后我告诉了你真相
And then when I did tell you the truth,
你很生气
you were so mad.
很受伤
And so hurt.
你不相信他就这么离开了
You could not believe that he left
连句再见都没有说
without even saying good-bye.
所以几年后当我的男朋友道格和我分手
So a couple years later when my boyfriend Doug and I broke up,
然后他离开
and he left...
我不可能再让你重新经受那份痛苦
there was no way I was gonna put you through that pain again.
你们关系那么好
You two had become so close, and...
你为了保护我而撒了谎
You lied to protect me.
但是  妈
But, Mom...
你为什么和其他的都分手了
why did you break up with all the others?
他们一直想要超出我能力范围的东西
They always wanted more than I could give.
你害怕了
You get scared.
我知道因为我也是这么想的
I know because I'm the same way...
也正因如此我给你做了点东西
which is why I made you something.
一份"拉尔夫之书"的补册
An addendum for "The Book of Ralph."
"向你"
"22 steps
"命中之人敞开心扉的22步"
to being open to the love of your life."
我对爱敞开心扉  只是有点挑剔
I'm open to love. I'm just picky.
妈  别骗我了
Mom, give me a break.
我们俩自从爸走后谁也没对爱敞开心扉
Neither one of us have been open to love since Dad left.
妈  在逃避疼痛的同时
And, Mom, by keeping that pain away...
我们也拒绝了
we're also closing ourselves off
爱所能带来了快乐
from the joy that love can bring.
我不认为我适合快乐
I don't think I'm cut out for joy.
但是我想让你有那份快乐  拉尔夫
But I want that joy for you, Ralph.
爱  快乐  所有的一切
Love, happiness, the whole kit and caboodle.
我想让你去追寻它
I want you to go find that.
不要担心我
And don't worry about me.
好吗  拉尔夫
Okay, Ralph?
妈  拜托
Come on, Mom.
我一直会是你的拉尔夫
I'll always be your Ralphy.
我现在有了新的理论
I now have a new theory.
我相信我找到了有效治愈噬血细胞综合征的方法
I believe I have found an effective cure for HLH.
此法将能剔除我对暗物质的需求
One that would eliminate my need for dark matter entirely.
对样本1-A米切·罗密欧的血液的分析
Analysis of Subject 1-A, Mitch Romero's blood,
揭示了暗物质注入健康的血细胞
reveals that dark matter infused with healthy blood cells
会创造出更强大的生物物质
to create an even stronger biological substance.
这种物质会治愈人体中的任何
This substance appears to heal any and all weaknesses
以及所有的弱点
in the human body...
包括被噬血细胞综合征影响的细胞
including cells affected by HLH.
我现在要开始人体试验
I will now commence human trials.
我需要更多
I need more.
生日快乐
什么鬼啊
What in tarnation?
嗨  亲爱的  我们有个小聚会吗
Hey, sweetie, we having a little get-together?
所以冰霜从没有过生日派对
So Frost has never had a birthday party,
所以我提议给她办一个
so I offered to throw her one.
她选了客人名单
She picked the guest list.
这是我的派对  如果我想生气就生气
It's my party, and I'll rage if I want to!
你好
Hey.
你错过了所有的欢乐
You're missing out on all the fun.
谢谢你办的派对
Thanks for the party.
我在想明年
I'm thinking next year,
我们去激流勇进
we go whitewater rafting.
你确实应该去
You should definitely do that.
你明年不会再出现在我的生日派对了对吗
You're not gonna be at my birthday party next year, are you?
任何时候你在危机之后谈论生活
Whenever you talk about life after Crisis,
你从不说你自己的
you never talk about yourself.
你要做的不仅仅是消失在危机中  对吗
You're gonna do more than just vanish in Crisis, aren't you?
我不知道怎么告诉他们
I don't know how to tell them.
试着我站在你这边
Try with me by your side.
巴里  总是守着这个秘密感觉很不对
Barry, keeping this secret all day hasn't felt right.
我们一起去告诉他们
Let's tell them together.
巴里和我没有与你们完全分享我们
Barry and I didn't share everything that we learned
对危机的所知
about Crisis, and...
你们应该知道真相
you guys deserve to know the truth.
监视者不仅警告我们危机会提前到来
The Monitor didn't just warn us that Crisis was coming early.
还有另一些事会发生
There was something else that he said had to happen.
当我把思想向未来投射的时候
When I projected my mind forward,
我看到了数十亿个可能的未来
I saw billions of possible futures.
唯一一条所有人活下来的时间线
The only timeline where everyone survives...
就是我死了的那条
was the one where I died.
我必须要在危机中死去
I have to die in Crisis.
你们没人可以试着救我
None of you can try and save me.
就在这里
It's here.